Mike North: 让我们来谈谈数组。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Let's touch on arrays.
到目前为止，我们一直在使用原始值
Right, so we've been working with
primitive values so far, and
我们有几个问题的例子。
with questions we got
a couple object examples.
这是一个非常直观的数组示例。
So here's an example of an array and
pretty intuitive.
表示数组的一种方法是在类型后面使用方括号，对吗？
One way of representing an array is to use
square brackets following a type, right?
这是一组数字。
So this is an array of numbers.
我们可以推33，正如你所期望的,
We can push 33, and as you would expect,
试图将一个字符串推入这个数组会导致一个问题。
trying to push a string into
this array will cause a problem.
现在，如果我们这里没有这个，我们就会遇到问题。
Now, if we didn't have this here,
we would run into issues.
这是一个 nevers 数组，听起来很糟糕。
That's an array of nevers, sounds bad.
数组的 nevers 在，它永远不会发生，它永远不会工作。
Array of nevers as in, it can never
happen, it's never going to work.
所以永远不要输入脚本的底部类型。
[LAUGH] So
never is type script bottom type.
当我们学习 top 和 top 的时候，我们会更详细地研究它
And we will look at that more in detail
later when we're studying top and
特别是底部类型。
bottom types specifically.
但请注意，我们在推动任何事情上都会遇到问题
But just note that we're gonna
have problems pushing anything at
都是为了这个。
all into this.
如果我们仔细想想这是有道理的,
And if we think about it
this is kind of makes sense,
如果你只能看第57行，你必须决定戒酒协会的类型,
if you could only look at line 57 and
you had to decide the type of aa,
你只能假设它是一个什么东西的数组，一个什么东西的数组。
all you can assume is that it's an array
of whatever, it's an array of something.
现在你可以说它是任何东西的数组,
Now you could say it's
an array of anything at all,
但是，迈克诺斯: 那将是危险的
but,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: That's gonna be dangerously
很灵活，对吧？
flexible, right?
所以一个 nevers 的数组，是的，它是一个数组。
So an array of nevers, yes it's an array.
但是没有额外的信息。
But without additional information.
没有为你提供一个好的、安全的选择所需的东西。
TypeScript doesn't have what it needs in
order to make a nice, safe choice for you.
这就是为什么数组声明。
So that's why for array declarations.
一开始是空的。
That start out as empty.
你得说清楚你要放什么进去。
You wanna be specific about
what you're putting in there.
如果我们有哪怕一个元素,
Now, if we had even one element,
我们可以做出合理的假设。
it's gonna be able to make
a reasonable assumption here.
所以如果你在某些情况下没有动力
So if you didn't have
motivation in situations
你已经开始的东西，肯定会在那里
where you already start out with
something that'll definitely be there and
然后有条件地加入其他东西。
then conditionally you add other stuff.
将其作为变量初始化放在声明本身中。
Putting that in the declaration itself
as the variable initialization.
现在你有动力去
Now you have motivation to go and
这样做，因为这样你就不用指定那个类型了。
do that, because it saves you from
having to actually specify that type.
如果你给它一些内容，它可以被推断出来。
It can be inferred if you
give it some contents at all.
Mike North: 那么，tuple 是个花哨的词。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So, tuple is a fancy word.
意思是数组。
Just means array.
它是一个固定长度的数组，和一个带有约定的数组。
It's an array of a fixed length, and
an array that comes with a convention.
所以如果我们定义一个可以包含街道地址的数据结构,
So if we were to define a data structure
that could contain a street address,
我们可以使用一个物体的属性名，比如门牌号，街道名,
we could use an object with property
names like house number, street name,
邮政编码，城市。
postal code, city.
然后我们可以在需要的时候把东西拿出来。
And then we can pluck
things out as we need them.
类似地，tuple 可以保存结构化的数据集。
Tuples, similarly,
can hold a structured set of data.
但是我们必须记住这里的惯例是,
But, we just have to remember
that the convention here is,
首先是门牌号,
the first thing is the house number,
第二件事是街名，最后一件事是邮政编码。
the second thing is the street name,
the last thing is the postal code.
我们仍然可以在那里获得强大的打字能力。
And we still get strong typing there.
所以这些数组的长度只能是4。
So these arrays can
only be of length four.
它们的成员类型必须与我们声明的完全一致。
And the types of their members must
be exactly as we declare them.
现在，这是从一个函数返回多个值的一个很好的方法。
Now, this is a great way of returning
multiple values from a function.
我很成功地完成了这次抓取，这是你的数据。
I was successful in making this fetch and
here is your data.
我没有成功地进行这次获取，这是您的错误消息，对吗？
I was unsuccessful in making this fetch,
and here is your error message, right?
一个不错的选择，如果你有一些东西，通过经常使用，可能会扔。
A nice alternative, if you have something
that, through regular use, might throw.
而不是抛出，这对异常错误很有好处,
Instead of throwing,
which is good for exceptional errors,
一些你没有计划的事情，这样你就可以像
things you didn't plan for,
this would allow you to return in like
对结果和细节数据表示赞成和反对。
a thumbs up a thumbs down for
the result and data about the details.
你可以看到这里我们检查了元组成员的类型,
You can see here that we get type
checking for members of a tuple,
我想指出一点，那就是让它变得紧凑
one thing I want to point
out that make it tight in
未来的迈克 · 诺斯: 你
the future
&gt;&gt; Mike North: You
在会员周围安装类型安全装置，但我相信。
get type safety around the members,
but I believe.
迈克 · 诺斯: 在 push 中没有类型安全。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: You don't
get type safety in push.
所以我们可以把这看作是一种推力,
So it's gonna regard this as
in terms of the type of push,
它可以接受字符串或数字。
it can take strings or numbers.
所以对于元组，你需要小心地设置它的值
So with tuples, you're gonna want to be
careful to just sort of set its value and
访问它的值
access its value and
不使用数组方法，因为它们不是真正的类型安全。
not use the array methods because
they're not really type safe.
实际上，没有办法安全地输入 push
There's actually no way to type,
to safely type push
以这样的方式，基于它当前拥有的元素数量。
In such a way that based on the number
of elements it currently has.
如果我们尝试逐步构建这个模型，我们可以
If we were to try to
incrementally build this up, we
不知道首先我们应该接受一个数字，然后我们应该接受一个字符串,
wouldn't know that first we should accept
a number, then we should accept a string,
然后我们接受一个字符串，然后我们接受一个数字。
then we should accept a string,
then we should accept a number.
这就需要我们基于数组更改中的状态
With that it will require us to kind
of based on state in the array change
这个函数的类型签名。
the type signature of this function.
无论如何，你不会这样使用元组。
And you don't use tuples this way, anyway.
因为唯一的方法得到一个有效的是设置它所有在一次和
Cuz the only way to get a valid
one is to set it all at once and
可以作为整个语句进行类型检查。
that can all be type checked
as a whole statement.
什么事？
Yes?
扬声器2: 如果你这样做，例如，希望有一个数组可以是
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: If you did, for example,
want to have an array that could be either
数字或者字符串，你会怎么做？
number or a string,
how would you go about doing that?
麦克 · 诺斯: 问得好。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Good question.
如果我给你看迈克 · 诺斯: 如果我
If I showed you
&gt;&gt; Mike North: If I
给你看了这个工具。
showed you this tool tip here.
等等，对不起，这是，迈克 · 诺斯: 这个工具提示。
Wait, sorry it's,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: This tool tip.
这里，这样一个例子。
So here, this kind of an example.
如果你读过这篇文章，比如有人能给我一次机会吗。
If you had read that,
like can someone give me a shot.
演讲者3: 或者那里的一个数字。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Or a number there.
字符串或数字。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: String or number.
它是字符串或数字括号，输入它们的数组。
It's string or number parentheses,
entered an array of them.
扬声器3: 你可以在函数中做一个字符串，就像我想要的
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: So you could do like a
string in a function like I wanna array of
字符串或函数返回这个总和？
strings or functions to return
back in this the sum of that?
迈克 · 诺斯: 正确 演讲者3: 好的，很好。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Correct.
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Okay, cool.
迈克 · 诺斯: 这是我们这堂课最后要讲的内容。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: And that's the last
thing we'll cover in this lecture.
演讲者3: 对不起 迈克 · 诺斯: 不，不,
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: I'm sorry.
&gt;&gt; Mike North: No, no,
不要因为带领我们走向,
do not apologize for
leading us to if anything,
你在帮我的忙，准备下一个部分。
you're doing me a favor and
teeing up the next sections.
还有其他问题吗？
Other questions about this?
说话人3: 你实际上可以把任何喜欢
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: You can'actually
just put any like
迈克 · 诺斯: 完全正确,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Totally, yep,
你可以做任何你总是可以提供一个类型缩进来放松东西。
you could do any You can always provide
a type indentation to loosen things up.
类似于我们的 let 和 const 示例，在创建这些元组时，对。
Similar to our let and const example,
when creating these tuples, right.
这些东西的长度是固定的。
These things of fixed length.
就像数组中的一对数字。
Like a pair of numbers in an array.
你经常需要或者总是需要指定你想要的类型。
You are going to often have to or
always have to specify the type you want.
为什么，因为在不干扰你的工作流程方面犯了错误。
Why, because erring on the side of
not interfering with your work flow.
类型脚本会将其视为一个数字数组。
Type script is gonna consider
this to be an array of numbers.
它不会认为这是一个包含两个数字的元组。
Right, it's not gonna consider this
to be a tuple containing two numbers.
所以你只需要在这里提供这个类型注释，因为它是一个漂亮的
So you just have to always provide this
type annotation here because it's a pretty
特殊的东西。
specific thing.
字符串文字类型也是如此，如果您想要一个类型为
Same goes with a string literal type,
if you wanted a string whose type was
只有弦麦克，仅仅说 x 等于麦克是不够的。
only the string Mike, it wouldn't be
enough to just say let x equal Mike.
你得说让 x: 迈克 · 迈克。
You'd have to say let x: Mike = Mike.
只有这样你才能得到那个非常非常具体的东西。
And only then would you get that really,
really specific thing.